<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[South Kent School]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[South Kent School]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/sks/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:29:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/sks/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>At South Kent School, athletics are part of everyday life. The school expects that each boy who spends time on the Hillside participates in a fitness oriented athletic offering at least two seasons of the year; the third season, he may participate in an extracurricular activity. The Physical Fitness option is limited to VI Form and Post-Graduate students. Each student is asked to contribute to a program designed to challenge him as well as build his selfesteem and confidence. The athletic program engages our students in developing teamwork by driving toward a common goal and learning that personal sacrifice can benefit the whole. If, for documented medical reasons, a boy cannot actively participate in the School’s athletic program, he is expected to work with the athletic trainers or serve one of the teams in another capacity.

South Kent’s interscholastic athletic schedules are very competitive. Frequently, the teams compete against much larger schools. SKS has a rich tradition of hard work and fair play. South Kent boys compete with pride and remain gentlemen in victory as well as in defeat. South Kent School is a member of the New England Preparatory School Athletic Council and the Hudson Valley Athletic League. Teams have the opportunity to participate in post-season tournaments and compete for league and New England titles. South Kent School adheres to HVAL and NEPSAC guidelines for athletes, coaches, officials and spectators.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/sks/at-south-kent-school-athletics-are-part-of-everyday-life-t/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7b4e44b9-6624-4454-9fb5-9e43d2ff1be2</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:29:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Redefining Education


With the foundational concepts of Sustainable Earth, Sustainable Design, and Sustainable Community, South Kent strives to involve students as an integral part in every step of what we do at the CFI. This programming goes beyond individual projects and extends to understanding ethics and values through real-world experiences. See below for Center for Innovation course offerings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/sks/redefining-education-with-the-foundational-concepts-of-sus/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0f838efa-1388-4afe-bed3-d0266e50dbd6</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:28:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Sustainable Community- Kat Droessler & Emily Carreiro
Dig into what it means to be a knowledgeable citizen of the world. This experience will include examining the pulse of campus life, world cultures (from food to belief systems and beyond) and regularly looking into how culture and society are affected by seasons by examining our own community on the Hillside. We will also learn to be mindful in our daily life and how sociology fits into each individual's Hero's Journey.

Sustainable Forestry 1 - Fall - Stan Vylet
Students will conduct a survey of the forest resources at SKS. The project will include field survey to identify dominant tree species and understory vegetation; non-native versus native species, some wildlife surveys, and mapping of forest data. SKS will work with partners with expertise in forest management. Students will present maps, species identification keys, and other data to the SKS community. Students will develop and begin a management plan for the forest resources at SKS. Student study will also take into consideration protecting water quality, preservation and/or creation of wildlife habitat, the potential for timber harvest, and possible reforestation of formerly agricultural use land. Field work will include plant/tree-identification and mapping; and removal of non-native invasive plant species. Students will present a management plan to the SKS community.

Sustainable Forestry 2 - Spring - Stan Vylet
Students will develop and begin implementation of forest management practices on the forested property on the South Kent School. Field work will include surveys for flora and fauna species as well as alteration of forest habitat. Possible projects include tree cloning of valuable species, experimental clearing and plantings of vegetation, and/or developing habitat suitable for various bird and mammal species of concern in the state of Connecticut. SKS will work with partners with expertise in habitat management and seek funding for projects. Students will present their findings to the SKS community.

Watershed Management 1 - Fall - MaryAnn Haverstock
Working from the Hatch Pond Watershed Based Plan finalized in 2014, students will continue to learn about watershed management, discuss natural resource assessments and design /implement sustainable engineering within their campus and Kent community.
Students will collaborate with other classes to design and build a hydroponic system as a demonstration of a sustainable ecosystem.
Students will work toward an assessment and map of proposed areas on campus for low impact development projects. This project will support the existing watershed plan recommendations.Students will support the local Weantinoge Heritage Land Trust in efforts to design, build and maintain trails in the Hatch and the nearby Mud Pond watersheds. Students may visit different watersheds throughout the semester to investigate macro invertebrates and gain an understanding of natural diversity within watersheds throughout the state.

Watershed Management 2 - Spring - MaryAnn Haverstock
Working in partnership with the Connecticut DEEP, students will monitor water quality in the Hatch Pond watershed and develop/implement plans for improving water quality, with a focus on water resource management including flooding and drought. Students will take samples from Hatch Ponds and conduct macroinvertebrate surveys throughout the Hatch Pond tributaries. Students will develop proposals for management of aquatic plants species and also work to manage water resources including flooding and drought. Students will present their findings to the SKS community.

Wetlands Restoration and Low Impact Development - Fall - Jesse Brennan
Working under the guide of the Watershed Management Plan, students will work to restore the waterways and wetlands around campus by removing unnatural waterway obstructions, invasive species, and environmentally harmful materials. As well, the class will look at ways to minimize the overall effects of campus development on the local watershed, including possible ways to improve current developments.

Sustainable Agriculture -Fall and Spring - Tonya Taylor & Kasey Clark - Open to All Forms
Students will be introduced to the principles, concepts and methods of sustainable agriculture in New England. Through hands-on labor, students will learn to grow and tend a vegetable garden, raise and care for livestock and how to prepare and preserve the harvest. Students will be responsible for tracking farm data, including labor inputs and production totals, to create a summary of farm productivity that can be archived and presented each term. Students will also engage in active discussions about the wider issues of sustainability, including food security, climate change, resource conservation and self-reliance.

Sustainable Technology Solutions (3rd and 4th Forms)- Fall and Spring Anthony Larson
This course will challenge students to create solutions to the real world requirements of sustainability at the Center for Innovation. Students will develop solutions using the SolidWorks CAD design suite and build a working prototype. Possible applications will be farm equipment, produce cleaning and irrigation. Students may also develop “lowtech” products with applications in third world countries or products for “farmhack”.

Automated Technology Systems (Now part of Robotics Class)-Spring Anthony Larson - Closed at this time
This course will challenge students to create solutions to the real world requirements of sustainability at the Center for Innovation. This engineering course will focus on defining problems that would benefit from automated solutions running under computer control. Students will develop programs and prototype systems to monitor or control a process at the Center for Innovation. Possible applications will be farm equipment, produce cleaning and irrigation. Students may also develop “lo tech” products with applications in third world countries.

Alternative Energy Solutions- Fall and Spring Anthony Larson - 5th, 6th, & PG Forms
This course will introduce various clean energy solutions such as wind, solar and fuel cells. Students will solve real world problems at the Center for Innovation including transportation, animal husbandry, greenhouses, farming and irrigation.

Historic Building Technology- Fall and Spring (Upper Forms) - Dr. Jed Struckus
Students investigate sustainable building trends to reduce energy consumption, resource consumption and waste production. Areas of investigation include building techniques, material usage and life cycle management. Known on campus as the “timber framing class”, this course is now in its fourth year. Students investigate sustainable building trends with a particular focus upon reducing energy consumption, using locally available building materials, and mastering building skills that have existed for thousands of years and yet remain the most efficient and enduring methods of construction. Consistent with the “Innovation” theme, students use and master tools and technologies that span hundreds of years of use and refinement. The course includes field trips to visit national leaders in the field, and culminates in the creation of usable structures or finished pieces of fine furniture.

Embedded Journalism - Lynn Worthington - 5th, 6th, & PG Forms
In this course, students create multimedia packages, learning how to produce short documentary films (videos) through hands-on experience in projects related to activities at the Center For Innovation. Topics will showcase a variety of activities that students are involved in at SKS. Key skills in the course will include researching background issues, interviewing, story board composition, camera work, script/narrative writing, oral presentation, and video editing. Students will also learn to work as part of production teams attached to groups working on any of the CFI classes running concurrently. This course is part of all three of the CFI Spheres: Sustainable Earth, Sustainable Design and Sustainable Community.

Ceramic Arts - Fall and Spring - John Funk & Brendan Moore - All Forms
This course is designed for students who have an interest in working with clay. Activities will provide a basic experience in making functional as well as sculptural pieces using a variety of techniques. This will include hand building using pinch pot, coil, slab, and wheel throwing methods. There will be an emphasis on the elements and principles of three-dimensional forms.

Entrepreneurship – Fall and Spring – Scott Farley - 5th, 6th, & PG Forms
This challenge-based learning course explores all aspects of entrepreneurship including generating ideas, analyzing economics, writing a business plan and generating funding. Working closely with the Center for Innovation (CFI,) students will generate their own ideas or use existing ideas within the CFI. Through structured assignments, case studies and guest lectures, students will learn about the innovation process, the fundamentals of a business plan, and the methods of getting funding, both traditional and nontraditional. The final goal of the course is a successful presentation to the board of CFI.

Open Source Software Development- Phil Darrin 3rd & 4th Form
“Here we are, 2013, we ALL depend on technology to communicate, to bank, and none of us know how to read and write code.” - will.i.am, Musician Black Eyed Peas“Our policy at Facebook is literally to hire as many talented engineers as we can find. There just aren't enough people who are trained and have these skills today.” - Mark Zuckerberg, Facebook Founder
According to Code.org, by 2020 there will be 1,000,000 more coding jobs than students who understand code. Students enrolled in the OSSD course will learn the coding language Python. The OSSD course requires no previous coding experience, and is almost entirely self-paced. Additionally, OSSD students may build their very own computer called the Raspberry Pi ($200 Fee). Finally, OSSD may also create a social site for high school students call HighSchoolPortfolio.com. Creative, self-motivated, team-players are welcomed to join.

Watershed Management: Biological Indicators, Improvement, and Sustainability - Will Morse - 3rd & 4th Form
America possesses a variety of water resources. There is much debate over how these resources should be, and are, managed; especially in an era of climate change and the problem of clean water and worldwide availability. Public lands, national parks, and other designated areas hold a large majority of these natural resources. From the water supplies of the Catskills, to the oil fisheries of Alaska, management practices are diverse and complex. This course looks into the economic and deep geological reasons and debates over management practices, with particular focus on watersheds and their use as indicators of climate change. After looking at these indicators, Students will ultimately be asked how we should use our water resources in the future to promote sustainable development, energy use, sustainable fisheries, and maximize available water for global distribution.

Near Space Balloon Launch – Fall – Mark Berghold (Third and Fourth Forms)
The objective of this CFI class is to prepare, launch into Near Space, and retrieve a weather balloon with an on-board flight computer and cameras.Students will be responsible for building the payload frame, configuring the flight computer to record data (temperature, pressure, GPS data, etc.), recording video from two on-board GoPros, predicting the flight path, filing a NOTAM (NOtice to AirMen) with the FAA to obtain approval for the flight, coordinating the successful recovery of the payload, and analyzing recorded flight data. The goal is to reach an altitude of 90,000 feet AND have a successful recovery of the airframe and collected data. No experience is necessary. Specific “mission assignments” (Electronic Systems Operator, Flight Trajectory Officer, et al.) will be determined early in the course.

Mars Rover Robotics Competition – Fall – Mark Berghold (Third and Fourth Forms)
Pairs of students will build several remote-controlled robots to compete in a “Mars Rover” competition at the end of the Fall Term. Teams’ robots will race against each other to complete specific tasks on a simulated martian terrain. Students may encounter “alien” life forms and additional obstacles during the course of their mission. The ability to work well on a team, patience, and a good sense of humor will be valuable assets for this exercise. No prior robotics experience is necessary. Students not directly involved in the construction of a robot will assist with the construction of the competition playing field and its obstacles.

Electric Car – Fall – Mark Berghold (Fifth and Sixth Forms)
Students will complete the construction of an Electric Car by end of term. Students will evaluate both the benefits as well as the obstacles (economic, political, and practical) to the widespread adoption of electric vehicles. The project will conclude with an on campus “drag race”/speed test.

Water Purification Challenge – Fall – Mark Berghold (Fifth and Sixth Forms)
Enteric and diarrheal diseases are the second-leading cause of child mortality, killing almost 1.7 million children. In India alone, over 4,000 children succumb daily to enteric and diarrheal diseases. While this number has been dropping in recent years, more can be done through (1) access/delivery of vaccines, (2) the adoption of more effective nutritional practices, and (3) improved water, sanitation, and hygiene systems. The task of this course is to explore and develop prototypes to address this last category. Two to three teams will be given a modest budget with which to develop an inexpensive, portable and effective water purification system. Final designs will be pitched “Shark Tank” style to a small group of CFI faculty for assessment. Students will be encouraged to use any recyclable material they might find on campus and to make some use of the School’s 3-D printers/carving machine. Final pitches will be evaluated on several criteria including, but not limited to, the unit’s cost, efficiency, business plan, marketing plan and each team’s demonstrated understanding of their product and strategy.

Methane BioDigester – Fall – Mark Berghold (Fifth and Sixth Forms)
Methane is a flammable gas that can come from both natural and manmade sources. Because of it its effectiveness in absorbing heat in the atmosphere, it is initially more devastating than CO2. Our primary goal will be to manufacture a small quantity of methane through the same process that is used to produce beer (controlled fermentation). Students will develop small-scale prototype methane digesters. Prototypes will be built in the Innovation and Sustainability Lab and tested at the Center for Innovation. The ultimate goal (Spring 2016) will be to provide an effective model for a larger scale system. This system would then heat the School’s greenhouse during the winter months and allow us to extend our growing season.

The Oral History of Kent - Mr. Pfeffer
The town of Kent, in conjunction with South Kent School, possesses a rich history that deserves to be heard and preserved. In The Oral History of Kent class, students will conduct interviews with either longtime local residents of Kent or key alumni of South Kent School. Students in this class will gain valuable skills in interpersonal communication, writing, editing, designing and more. Students who enjoy socializing, networking and making connections, history, and language arts will benefit from this course.Through the oral history given by the interviewees, students will first have the privilege of learning about Kent’s past through first-person accounts; they will then transcribe and compile their interviews into a pamphlet to be made available for the South Kent community to read and enjoy. Students involved will be personally credited on the published work.

Mindfulness - Mr. Beer
Mindful self-inquiry is designed for students to investigate the concept and applications of mindfulness, and to investigate into the nature of their own mind and being. My intention for the course is for students to develop an understanding of mindfulness as a way of reducing stress in their lives as well enhance their educational achievement. The curriculum of this course includes: focused attention on breath and sensory experiences; awareness of thoughts and emotions; movement practices; caring or kindness practices; and ongoing critique of mindfulness for stress reduction in student life. Students learn the skills over time, and the intention is that, through sustained practice, mindful awareness becomes a positive way for students to enhance social and emotional learning, strengthen attention and concentration for academics and personal relationships, and foster a student’s overall well-being.Students will participate in a progression of classes to explore three primary mindfulness-based stress reduction meditation exercises: sitting meditation; body-scan; and yoga, which encourage non-judgemental observation and acceptance of bodily sensations, cognitions, emotional states. The exercises will be useful for students in reframing certain approaches to their academic and social life. Furthermore, students’ experience in cultivating their personal practice will be enriched through weekly discussions and critiques with other students in the course.

Architecture - Mr. Chavka
This is an advanced course open to 5th, 6th and PG’s that concentrates on the field of architectural design. Students will incorporate the elements and principles of design, architectural styles and post and beam construction to create a multiuse building at the Center For Innovation. Green and sustainable building technologies will be investigated and their use emphasized. Assignments include gathering customer inventory and analysis, developing architectural design documents, conceptual design drawings, floor plans, elevation drawings, detail drawings, renderings and models. Students will use the SolidWorks and Chief Architect CAD package.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/sks/sustainable-community-kat-droessler-and-emily-carreiro-dig-in/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1e98afa5-ec94-4d2f-b19d-a63f8d2972ca</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:28:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Who We Are</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/sks/who-we-are/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">165ec3df-fa03-4535-a0b8-c6fd8c2910e2</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:16:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>South Kent School "Excellence for Boys"</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/sks/south-kent-school-excellence-for-boys/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4e9acc84-8235-4103-9709-9f04642d6a7b</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:16:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>South Kent School's Center for Innovation: </p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/sks/7876c429-5357-4081-8a70-cee94022c1e7/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7876c429-5357-4081-8a70-cee94022c1e7</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:21:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>